Guide to the Larry Kramer Papers YCAL MSS 722
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- July 2019 Acquisition, 1941-2019; 16.8 Linear Feet (26 boxes) + 1 broadside
  - Writings, 9.1 Linear Feet (12 boxes)
    - Books
      - The American People
        - Background materials "to plug in", 2003–2010, undated; 4 folders (Box 242)
        - Background materials "to plug in", 2003–2010, undated; 2 folders (Box 243)
        - Early outline, typescript printouts, corrected, [1990s?] (Box 237)
        - Master outline, typescript printouts, corrected, 1995 May (Box 237)
        - Notebooks, undated; 2 folders (Box 237)
        - Holograph notes, 2010–2017, undated (Box 237)
        - Drafts, typescript printouts, notes, and research materials, 1994–2010, undated; 4 folders (Box 237)
        - Notes and research materials, 2006–2009, undated (Box 237)
        - Jerry Zipkin research materials, 1987–1995 (Box 237)
        - Anthony Fauci research materials, with correspondence, 1999–2004, undated (Box 237)
        - Philadelphia draft fragments, typescript printouts, and research materials, 1999–2001, undated; 2 folders (Box 237)
        - First Great North American plague draft fragments, typescript printouts, corrected, [2003?] (Box 237)
        - First Hairy Men draft fragments, typescript printouts, corrected, [2003?] (Box 237)
        - Your Roving Conductor draft fragments, typescript printouts, corrected, [2003?] (Box 237)
        - Idi Amin research materials, 2003 (Box 237)
        - It's All Right to be Rich [empty], undated (Box 237)
        - Bosco/Monkeys draft fragments, typescript printouts, corrected, [2003?] (Box 237)
        - Tortura draft fragments, typescript printouts, corrected, [2003?] (Box 237)
        - The First Homosexuals draft fragments, holograph and typescript printouts, corrected, [2003?] (Box 237)
        - First Punics draft fragments, typescript printouts, corrected, [2003?] (Box 237)
        - Israel research materials, 2003 (Box 237)
        - Yaddah draft fragments, typescript printouts, corrected, [2003?] (Box 237)
        - Draft fragments, typescript printouts, corrected, undated (Box 237)
        - Early? draft A, typescript printouts, 77 pages, undated (Box 238)
        - Early? draft B, typescript printouts, 105 pages, undated (Box 238)
        - Draft, typescript printouts, annotated, 1459 pages, 2005 December 19; 9 folders (Box 238)
        - Draft A, typescript printouts, 74 pages, undated (Box 238)
        - Draft B, typescript printouts, 136 pages, undated (Box 238)
        - Draft C, typescript printouts, corrected, 651 pages, undated; 4 folders (Box 238)
        - "Junior's Last Dance" draft fragment, typescript printouts, corrected, undated (Box 238)
        - Draft fragments, typescript printouts, corrected, 2010, undated (Box 238)
        - Draft D, typescript printouts, corrected, 115 pages, undated (Box 238)
        - Draft E, typescript printouts, corrected, 68 pages, undated (Box 238)
        - First and second drafts, typescript printouts, corrected, circa 2010 (Box 238)
        - First and second drafts, typescript printouts, corrected, circa 2010; 19 folders (Box 239)
        - First and second drafts, typescript printouts, corrected, circa 2010; 5 folders (Box 240)
        - Third draft A, typescript printouts, corrected, circa 2010; 10 folders (Box 240)
        - Third draft A, typescript printouts, corrected, circa 2010; 3 folders (Box 244)
        - Third draft B, typescript printouts, corrected, circa 2010 (Box 240)
        - Draft fragment, typescript printouts, corrected, circa 2010 (Box 240)
        - Third draft C, "Larry corrections," typescript printouts, corrected, 2010 August; 2 folders (Box 240)
        - Editor's notes by Joy Johannessen, 2010–2012, undated; 3 folders (Box 240)
        - Draft fragments and notes, typescript printouts, corrected, 2011, undated (Box 241)
        - The Brutality of Fact draft A, typescript printouts, corrected, 177 pages, circa 2011; 2 folders (Box 241)
        - The Brutality of Fact draft B, typescript printouts, corrected, 614 pages, undated; 4 folders (Box 241)
        - The Brutality of Fact draft C, typescript printouts, corrected, 532 pages, undated; 3 folders (Box 241)
        - "Twain" draft fragment, typescript printouts, corrected, undated (Box 241)
        - Editor's notes by Joy Johannessen, 2013 (Box 241)
        - Reviews, 2015 (Box 241)
      - Faggots
        - Preface by Reynold Price (photocopy), with correspondence, 2000 January 19 (Box 241)
        - German edition book cover, undated (Box 241)
    - Screenplays
      Includes Kramer's scripts, notes, and correspondence related to the 2014 HBO production of The Normal Heart, as well as screenplay drafts for a sequel film. Correspondents include director Ryan Murphy.
      - The Normal Heart
        - Contracts, 2010 (Box 247)
        - Early drafts, typescript printouts, corrected, undated; 2 folders (Box 241)
        - Draft, typescript printouts, with correspondence, 2012 (Box 241)
        - Drafts, typescript printouts, with correspondence and notes, 2013; 2 folders (Box 241)
        - Draft, typescript printouts, corrected, 2013 March (Box 241)
        - Production draft, typescript printouts, 2013 April 25 (Box 241)
        - Promotional ephemera, undated (Box 241)
        - Murphy, Ryan correspondence, undated (Box 241)
        - "The Normal Heart Part Two" contracts, 2014 (Box 241)
        - "The Normal Heart Part Two" draft, undated (Box 241)
      - Women in Love
        - Lobby card, 1969 (Box 258)
    - Plays
      Includes drafts, correspondence, playbills, and ephemera for Kramer's plays, as well as reworked scripts for an unproduced revival of The Destiny of Me with Joe Mantello.
      - The Destiny of Me
        - Unproduced revival with Joe Mantello, drafts and correspondence, 2011–2012, undated; 2 folders (Box 241)
        - Unproduced revival with Joe Mantello, drafts and correspondence, 2011–2012, undated (Box 245)
        - Draft, typescript printouts, corrected, 2012 January (Box 245)
        - Revised draft, typescript printouts, corrected, 2012 February 4 (Box 245)
        - Revised draft, typescript printouts, with correspondence and background materials, 2012 February 5–April 2 (Box 245)
        - Benefit reading ephemera, 2018 June 25 (Box 245)
      - A Minor Dark Age
        - Printed version (photocopy), with front matter, undated (Box 245)
        - Drafts, typescript printouts, corrected, with background materials, 2005, undated (Box 245)
      - The Normal Heart
        - Public Theatre production playbill, reviews, and clippings, 2004 (Box 245)
        - Broadway production playbill and correspondence, 2011 (Box 245)
        - Broadway production clippings, 2011 (Box 246)
        - Arena Stage production materials and ephemera, 2012 (Box 245)
    - Shorter Works and Other Writings
      Includes Kramer's articles, essays, journal entries, scripts, speeches, notes, and research material.
      - "2,339 and counting," advertisement in The Village Voice, 1983 October 4 (Box 258)
      - Articles, 2002–2018, undated (Box 246)
      - "Dolce Vita/Darling," typescript, corrected, with holograph notes, undated (Box 246)
      - Journal entries, typescript and holograph, 1978–1979 (Box 246)
      - Journal entries, typescript printouts, 1989–1994 (Box 246)
      - "Journal of the Plague Years," typescript, 1988 (Box 246)
      - "Last Word," column for The Advocate, photocopy, 1994, undated (Box 246)
      - "Miscellaneous writings" [articles], 1990–1993, undated (Box 246)
      - "Name an AIDS High Command," op-ed for The New York Times, 1992 (Box 246)
      - Notebook, undated (Box 246)
      - Notes, 1980, undated (Box 246)
      - Penelope Mortimer writing class assignments, typescript, with holograph annotations by Mortimer, 1974–1975; 2 folders (Box 246)
      - "Please Know, A Letter from Larry Kramer", undated (Box 247)
      - "Read This and Live," The Village Voice, 1989 June 27 (Box 258)
      - Remarks and speeches, 2000–2015 (Box 247)
      - "Remarks to the U.S. Conference on AIDS," drafts, typescript printouts, corrected, 2018 (Box 247)
      - Research materials
        - 1978–1996 (Box 247)
        - 1999–2000, 2 folders (Box 247)
        - 2001–2006 (Box 247)
        - 2005–2010, 2 folders (Box 247)
        - 2005–2010 (Box 248)
        - 2006–2008 (Box 258)
        - 2011–2017 (Box 248)
        - James A. Garfield, 2010 (Box 248)
        - Southern Poverty Law Center, 2005 (Box 248)
        - William Roger and Cal Thomas, 1993 (Box 248)
      - "Sexopolis," screenplay, typescript and holograph, corrected, [1980s] (Box 248)
      - "Some Thoughts While Living with the Amoebas for the Fourth Time", undated (Box 248)
      - "The Tragedy of Today's Gays," speech typescript printouts, 2004 (Box 248)
      - Various writings, 1984–2000, undated (Box 248)
      - "A Visit to Washington," typescript printouts, corrected, 1987 (Box 248)
  - Correspondence, 0.7 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
    This series consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence and email printouts from writers, artists, actors, collaborators, editors, producers, friends, fans, and others involved in publishing, television, and theatre. Correspondents include physician Anthony Fauci, playwright Tony Kushner, and theater director Joe Mantello.
    Organized into two groupings: Alphabetical, and Chronological.
    - Alphabetical
      Some correspondence in this series was removed from printed material that has been cataloged separately from the collection.
      Arranged by correspondent.
      - Bomer, Matt, undated (Box 249)
      - Canning, Sandra, undated (Box 249)
      - De Blasio, Bill, 2018 (Box 249)
      - Fauci, Anthony, undated (Box 249)
      - Fox, Cecil, 2006–2007; 2 folders (Box 249)
      - Hart, Bill, 2011 (Box 249)
      - Kinsolving, Susan, 2011 (Box 249)
      - Kushner, Tony, 2009, 2018 (Box 249)
      - Laubenstein, Priscilla [letters and other material removed from a copy of Tales of Linda], 2011–2015 (Box 249)
      - Leonard, Michael [including note removed from a copy of Michael Leonard: A Master of Ambiguity (Paintings, Drawings, and Portraits)], 2013, undated (Box 249)
      - Lieberson, Sanford, 1983, 2007 (Box 249)
      - Mantello, Joe, 2011 (Box 249)
      - Murphy, Ryan, 2018 (Box 249)
      - Piner, Carmen [letter removed from a copy of Cobalt Club], 2017 October 24 (Box 249)
      - Robinson, David Michael, 2004 (Box 249)
      - Roth, Daryl, 2011 (Box 249)
      - Rudin, Scott, 2006, 2017 (Box 249)
      - Ruffalo, Mark, 2013 (Box 249)
      - Schwalbe, Will, 2009–2014 (Box 249)
      - Surratt, Jerl [note removed from a copy of A Blind Bit of Notice], 2017 April (Box 249)
      - Wiener, Michael H., 2015 (Box 249)
    - Chronological
      - 1990–1994 (Box 249)
      - 2000–2007 (Box 249)
      - 2008 (Box 249)
      - 2009 (Box 249)
      - 2010–2011 (Box 250)
      - 2012–2013 (Box 250)
      - 2014 (Box 250)
      - 2016 (Box 250)
      - 2017–2019 (Box 250)
      - undated (Box 250)
  - AIDS Activism Files, 0.5 Linear Feet (1 box) + 1 broadside
    AIDS Activism Files consists of materials related to Kramer's activism and involvement with AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power, such as newsletters, posters, and publications. The series also contains files created by ACT UP members Jim Eigo, Tracy Morgan, and Maxine Wolfe, including photocopies of Maxine Wolfe's papers at the Lesbian Herstory Archive.
    Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - ACT UP
      - 1987–1990 (Box 251)
      - Eigo, Jim files, 2007; 2 folders (Box 251)
      - Ephemera, undated (Box 251)
      - Goldberg, Ron, "ACT UP: An Activist's Timeline (1987–1994)", 2008 (Box 251)
      - Morgan, Tracy files, 2012 (Box 251)
      - Treatment and Date Committee, 1990–1991 (Box 251)
      - Wolfe, Maxine files
        - General [1990–1997], 2008 (Box 251)
        - Barbara McClintock Project [1992–1994], 2008 (Box 251)
        - "Read It to ACT UP" newsletters [1993–1994], 2008 (Box 251)
        - "Tell It to ACT UP" newsletters [1990–1992], 2008; 3 folders (Box 251)
    - Leaflet by United Front Against Racism and Capitalism-Imperialism and Communistcadre, "AIDS is germ warfare by the U.S. Gov't against gays & blacks!", circa 1986 (Box 258)
    - Protest sign, "And I'm Marilyn Monroe", undated (Box 259 (Broadside))
    - Subway poster, "Deadlier than the Virus" [Stephen C. Joseph, Commissioner of Health, New York City], circa 1989 (Box 259 (Broadside))
    - Treatment Action Group, "AIDS Research at the NIH: A Critical Review", 1992 (Box 251)
  - Personal Papers, 4.8 Linear Feet (7 boxes)
    Personal Papers consist of event ephemera, press clippings, business and financial papers, family papers, photographs, subject files, and other personal papers. There is also a group of files collected by Kramer's brother Arthur Kramer, which Larry inherited upon his death in 2008. Materials include Kramer family papers, correspondence between the brothers and Arthur's wife Alice, and correspondence from Larry during his time at Yale and while he was working as a screenwriter in London. Arthur collected clippings about Larry and his work throughout his career, beginning with Women in Love in 1969.
    Organized into two groupings: General, and Arthur Kramer Papers. Each is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - General
      - ACT UP exhibit, 2010 (Box 252)
      - Agenda, 2015 (Box 252)
      - Archive, 2008–2019 (Box 252)
      - Clippings and press
        - Clippings, 1992–2016, undated; 2 folders (Box 252)
        - Magazines, 1997–2010; 3 folders (Box 252)
        - Magazines, 2013–2018; 4 folders (Box 257)
        - Newspapers, 1998–2018 (Box 258)
      - Events
        - 1994–2018, undated (Box 253)
        - Events honoring Larry Kramer, 2008–2019 (Box 253)
        - Tony Awards, 2013 (Box 253)
        - 92nd Street Y, "Larry Kramer: A Tribute Evening," with script by Tony Kushner, signed, 2004, 2016 (Box 253)
      - Financial papers, 2006–2016, undated (Box 253)
      - Hate mail, 1991 (Box 253)
      - How to Survive a Plague, 2016–2017 (Box 253)
      - Kramer, Arthur, death certificate (photocopy), will and letter to daughter Andrea, 2008 (Box 253)
      - Kramer, Rea, Red Cross certificate, 1963 (Box 253)
      - Legal papers, 2009, 2017 (Box 253)
      - McFarlane, Rodger, receipts for Larry Kramer's care, 2001–2002 (Box 253)
      - McFarlane, Rodger, receipts for Larry Kramer's care, 2001–2002 (Box 254)
      - Medical papers, 2012–2017, undated; 4 folders (Box 254)
      - Notes, undated (Box 254)
      - Photographs, 2008, undated (Box 254)
      - Publishing files, 2013, 2018 (Box 254)
      - Real estate, 2008 (Box 254)
      - Small objects, undated (Box 256)
      - Various clippings, 2008–2016, undated (Box 254)
      - Yale, 2009, undated (Box 254)
    - Arthur Kramer Papers
      - American Academy of Arts and Letters Ceremonial, 1996 (Box 255)
      - Certificates, Court of Appeals and District Court, 1957 (Box 255)
      - Clippings, 1994–2009 (Box 255)
      - Correspondence
        - Letters from Arthur Kramer to family, 1944, undated (Box 255)
        - Letters from Arthur Kramer to Larry Kramer, 1993 (Box 255)
        - Letters from Larry Kramer to family, 1952–1954, undated (Box 255)
        - Letters from Larry Kramer to Arthur Kramer and family, 1961–1969; 2 folders (Box 255)
        - Letters from Larry Kramer to Arthur and Alice Kramer, 1975–2000 (Box 255)
        - Letters to Arthur Kramer from various correspondents, 1945–1953, undated (Box 255)
        - Printed emails, 1999–2007 (Box 255)
        - Unsorted, 1993–2004 (Box 255)
      - Kramer, Alice, 2015, undated (Box 255)
      - Kramer, Larry, school files, 1941, 1953 (Box 255)
      - Kramer, Larry, wills, 1996, 2001 (Box 255)
      - Larry Kramer Institute for Lesbian and Gay Studies at Yale, 2003, undated (Box 255)
      - Letter to the editor of The New York Herald Tribune, 1952 August (Box 255)
      - Look magazine, with article on Women in Love, 1970 (Box 257)
      - MCI Communications, 1988 (Box 255)
      - Rich, Frank, "Introduction to Women in Love" (Box 255)
      - School records, 1946 (Box 255)
      - Yale papers, 1948, undated (Box 255)
  - Computer and Audiovisual Media, 1.7 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
    Boxes 253-254 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Boxes 255-256 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Computer Media
      Includes Kramer's born digital files on hard drives, floppy disks, and zip disks.
      - Computer media, undated (Box 260)
      - Computer media, undated (Box 261)
    - Audiovisual Media
      Includes audio and video recordings of Kramer's interviews and medical procedures.
      Arranged alphabetically by title.
      - Audiocassette
        - Gore Vidal/Larry Kramer, 1992 September 24 (Box 262)
      - Videocassettes
        - Larry Kramer liver transplant, tape 1, 2001 December 21 (Box 262)
        - Larry Kramer liver transplant, tape 2, 2001 December 21 (Box 262)
        - Larry Kramer liver transplant, tape 3, 2001 December 21 (Box 262)
        - Larry Kramer liver transplant, tape 4, 2001 December 21 (Box 262)
        - Larry Kramer liver transplant, tape 1, 2001 December 21 (Box 263)
        - Larry Kramer liver transplant, tape 2, 2001 December 21 (Box 263)
        - Larry Kramer liver transplant, tape 3, 2001 December 21 (Box 263)
        - Larry Kramer liver transplant, tape 4, 2001 December 21 (Box 263)
        - "One Angry Man: Larry Kramer," ABC News Nightline (1 of 6), 2001 August 29 (Box 263)
        - "One Angry Man: Larry Kramer," ABC News Nightline (2 of 6), 2001 August 29 (Box 263)
        - "One Angry Man: Larry Kramer," ABC News Nightline (3 of 6), 2001 August 29 (Box 263)
        - "One Angry Man: Larry Kramer," ABC News Nightline (4 of 6), 2001 August 29 (Box 263)
        - "One Angry Man: Larry Kramer," ABC News Nightline (5 of 6), 2001 August 29 (Box 263)
        - "One Angry Man: Larry Kramer," ABC News Nightline (6 of 6), 2001 August 29 (Box 263)